Preliminary Guide to the Howard Sayre Weaver Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Howard Sayre Weaver papers
1960-1979
MS 1259
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10
Correspondence, subject files, administrative files, financial papers, and film notes largely documenting Weaver's tenure as dean of the Yale School of Art and Architecture, 1968-1974. Also included are materials from the Yale New Haven Educational Corporation, the Hills Art Co-op, and the New Haven Foundation.
Weaver, Howard Sayre
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Yale University Media Design Studio, 1980.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Howard S. Weaver: advisor to University Publications, Yale University Press, 1959-1960; assistant director, 1960-1964; acting Secretary of Yale University, 1963-1964; associate secretary and advisor to the president of Yale University, 1964-1968; Dean of the School of Art and Architecture, Yale University, 1967-1974; director, Media Design Studio, 1974-.
Biographical / Historical
Howard Sayre Weaver, Director of the Media Design Studio and former Dean of the School of Art and Architecture, died April 23, 1982 at his home in Guilford, Connecticut. He was fifty-seven.
A native of Fredonia, N.Y., Weaver entered Yale with the Class of 1945W but left college to serve as an Air Corps pilot in the Far East. He returned to Yale at the end of the war and received his B.A. degree in 1948. After working for a few years, he joined the U.S. Foreign Service and was assigned to Thailand. He later became European Director of the Free Europe Press in Munich, Germany, before returning to Yale in 1959 as Assistant Director of the Yale University Press. He subsequently served as Associate Secretary of the University and Director of External Relations before becoming Acting Dean of the School of Art and Architecture. He became Dean in 1968 and served until 1974.
Weaver organized the Media Design Studio, dedicated to the teaching and production of films. He was also Director of the Poynter Fellowship Program.
His interest in flying, developed as a B-25 pilot in China and Burma during World War II, continued throughout his life. He was a leader in the Yale Aviation Club, an extracurricular program for students.
He is survived by his wife, Deborah Drummond Weaver; two sons, Howard, Jr., of Guilford, and George of Maine; three daughters, Sayre Andre of North Dakota, Stephanie Weaver of Guilford, and Deborah Weaver of Boston; a sister, Ruth Pinkerton of Florida; and a brother, George B. Weaver of Fredonia, N.Y.
(Taken from Yale Alumni Magazine and Journal, 1982 May).
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, subject files, administrative files, financial papers, and film notes largely documenting Weaver's tenure as dean of the Yale School of Art and Architecture, 1968-1974. Also included are materials from the Yale New Haven Educational Corporation, the Hills Art Co-op, and the New Haven Foundation.
Educators; Weaver, Howard Sayre; Hills Art Co-op (New Haven, Conn.); New Haven Educational Corporation; New Haven Foundation; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. School of Art and Architecture
- Inventory
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence, subject files, administrative files, financial papers, and films pertaining to Howard Sayre Weaver. The papers appear to have been generated during his tenure as Dean of the School of Art and Architecture, and include materials from the Yale-New Haven Educational Corporation, the Hills Art Co-op, and the New Haven Foundation. The collection has not been fully processed.
  - Correspondence and subject files
    - 1964-1965 (Box 1)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 2)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 3)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 4)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 5)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 6)
  - Yale-New Haven Educational Corporation: Administrative and reference files, 1966-1970 (Box 7)
  - Yale-New Haven Educational Corporation: Administrative and reference files, 1960s-1970s (Box 8)
  - Yale-New Haven Educational Corporation: Administrative and reference files, 1960s-1970s (Box 9)
  - Hills Art Co-op, 1960s-1970s (Box 9)
  - CETV, 1960s-1970s (Box 9)
  - New Haven Foundation, 1960-1970s (Box 9)
  - Appointment notebooks, 1966-1971 (Box 9)
  - Printing Service budget notebooks, 1960-1969 (Box 9)
  - Kingman Brewster speeches (notebooks), 1963-1968 (Box 10)
  - Film notes: "Slaughter-House Five" documentary, undated (Box 10)
  - Film notes: "Marigolds", undated (Box 10)
  - Correspondence re: "The Making of Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid", 1970-1971 (Box 10)